Finding aid to Why Are You Marching? interviews and 2017 Women's March photographs SSC.MS.00799
Sophia Smith Collection
Why Are You Marching?: January 2017 Women's March interviews, photographs, and website
2016 - 2017
Sophia Smith Collection
Hartnett, Annie
SSC.MS.00799
.0170 Gigabytes (220 digital files)
1 website
Scope and Contents
The collection contains sixteen brief interviews with participants in the Women's Marches on January 21, 2017, the the day after Donald J. Trump's inauguration. Marches took place in Washington, D.C, and across the country.
This project, created by Annie Hartnett, Kathryn Rogers, and Anne-Charlotte Patterson, hoped to tell the story of why so many women were marching on that day and what they hoped to achieve. The project also aimed to offer a glimpse into what diverse women are thinking and feeling at this pivotal moment in history. Most of the interviews were conducted via email or telephone.
Included in the collection are transcripts of interviews, audio recordings for five interviews, 140 still images of the march and some photos of interviewees; and the archived web site, entitled "Why Are You Marching?" (https://medium.com/whyareyoumarching). The website was captured in June 2019 and includes many of these interviews and photos.
Conditions Governing Access
Some of the interviews in this collection have restrictions on access. Please see the notes attached to an individual interview for information about restrictions that apply to it.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The project was created by Annie Hartnett, Kathryn Rogers, and Anne-Charlotte Patterson who donated the interviews and photographs to the Sophia Smith Collection in February 2019.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
This collection contains materials received from the donor in digital form that are not currently available online. Please consult with Special Collections staff to request access to this digital content.
Women's rights-United States-History-Sources; Demonstrations--United States--Photographs; Feminism--United States--21st century; Pro-choice movement--United States; Women's March on Washington (2017); Hartnett, Annie; Rogers, Kathryn; Patterson, Anne-Charlotte; Rogers, Kathryn; Patterson, Anne-Charlotte; B., Darren; Joseph, Dolly; Kavanaugh, Andrea; Nelson, Dara; Megan, Kate Nelson; Sabbag, Evelyn; Smith, Adriana; Spindler, Irene; Stringer, Laura; Syed, Abeer; Veloux, Andre; Washington, Ebony; Watts, Shannon; Willis, Karen
- Interviews
  - Transcript of interview of Darren B. and photo, 2017-01; 1 oral histories (1 transcript)
    Conditions Governing Access
    The narrator has requested that her last name not be made public. A redacted version of the transcript is available.
  - Transcript of interview of Dolly Joseph and photo, 2017-01; 1 oral histories (1 transcript)
  - Transcript of interview of Andrea Kavanaugh and photo, 2017-01; 1 oral histories (1 transcript)
  - Transcript of interview of Dara Nelson and photo, 2017-01; 1 oral histories (1 transcript)
    The narrator has requested that an access agreement form be signed prior to use of her interview. Contact Special Collections staff for more information.
  - Transcript of interview of Megan Kate Nelson, 2017-01; 1 oral histories (1 transcript)
  - Transcript of interview of Evelyn Sabbag and photo, 2017-01; 1 oral histories (1 transcript)
  - Transcript of interview of Adriana Smith and photo, 2017-01; 1 oral histories (1 transcript)
  - Interview of Irene Spindler and photo, 2017-01; 1 oral histories (1 transcript and 1 audio recording)
    - Transcript of interview of Irene Spindler
    - Audio interview with Irene Spindler
  - Transcript of interview of Laura Stringer, 2017-01; 1 oral histories (1 transcript)
  - Interview of Abeer Syed, 2017-01; 1 oral histories (1 transcript and 1 audio recording)
    - Transcript of interview of Abeer Syed
    - Audio interview of Abeer Syed
  - Transcript of interview of Andre Veloux and photo, 2017-01; 1 oral histories (1 transcript)
  - Interview of Ebony Washington, 2017-01; 1 oral histories (1 transcript and 1 audio recording)
    - Transcript of interview of Ebony Washington
    - Audio interview with Ebony Washington
  - Interview of Shannon Watts, 2017-01; 1 oral histories (1 transcript and 1 audio recording)
    - Transcript of interview of Shannon Watts
    - Audio interview with Shannon Watts
  - Transcript of interview of Karen Willis and photo, 2017-01; 1 oral histories (1 transcript)
- Women's March 1.21.2017 photos, 2017 January; 0.038 Gigabytes (140 digital files)
- Why Are You Marching? 1.21.2017 project website, 2016-2017; 1 website